(忆往昔)
我现在已经难辨真假了
I'm having a difficult time figuring out what's real.
萨姆  你从未离开过
You never left Sam.
你还是和我一起在笼子里
You are still in the cage with me.
让我看下你手
Let me see your hand.
你受伤的时候我跟你在一起  我给你缝的针
I was with you when you cut it, I sewed it up.
这是真的
This is real.
或许我是个怪物
I might be a freak.
但我能控制得了
But I'm managing it.
-镇上有活干  -尸体在哪儿
- There was a job in town. - Where's the body?
我放她走了
I let her go
为什么
Why?
你了解我  你知道我是什么样的人
You know me. You know the kind of person I am.
她在杀人  伙计
She's dropping bodies, man,
所以我们就得杀她
which means we got to drop her.
为了救我她杀了她母亲
She killed her own mom to save me.
很抱歉  但事情就这么简单
I'm sorry, but it's that simple.
她不会了
She's done.
相信我
Trust me.
迪恩  求你了
Dean, please.
好吧
Okay.
你改不了你的本性
You are what you are.
你还会再杀人的
You will kill again.
对不起
I'm sorry.
(如今)
(密歇根州  迪尔伯恩)
怎么会这样
That's impossible.
没事了
You're okay.
Oh, you're okay.
不要
No!
[邪恶力量 第7季第4集]
萨姆
Sam.
感觉好怪
Feels wonky.
什么
What?
做这种常规的活儿
Working a regular job.
如果利维坦那边出事的话鲍比会打电话的
Bobby'll call if anything flares up on the Leviathan front.
与此同时  你知道你想做这个案子的  迪恩
In the meantime, you know you want to work this case, Dean.
电话里警察听起来好像手足无措
Cop on the wire sounded dumbfounded.
那是必须的
No arguments.
这样很好  明白吗
It's kind of nice, you know?
我们也该做点没劲的活儿了
We're due for a little cut and dry.
还有
And, uh...
你看起来不错
You seem good.
是的
I am.
至少就我而言
For me.
对了
By the way...
谢谢你
Thank you.
为了什么
For?
为艾米
Amy.
我知道你并不想放她走的
I know you didn't want to let her go,
但把她放走是对的
but it was the right thing to do.
所以  谢谢
So, thanks.
不客气
No problem.
欢迎来到疯狂镇  一人死亡
Welcome to crazytown, population -- one dead guy.
他是谁
Who was he?
马修·哈蒙德
Uh, Matthew Hammond.
貌似是被撞死的
Seems to have been crushed to death.
被什么撞死的
By?
如果这不是十楼的话  我会说是车
Well, if we weren't on the tenth floor, I'd say by a car.
指针晃得好厉害
It's going crazy.
是鬼魂作怪吗
Some kind of ghost?
还带着驾照
With a license?
《杀人执照》(一部老电影)
License to kill.
你还有心情开玩笑
Seriously?
发现什么了
What do you got?
不知道  像什么粉末
I don't know. Looks like some kind of powder.
硫磺吗
Sulfur?
不是  就是土
No. Just dirt.
可能是被附身了
Could be "Christine"-like.
即使被附身的车也不可能爬楼梯啊
Even possessed cars can't do stairs.
应该是鬼一类的东西
It's something spectral.
你看这个
Check this out.
"戒酒十年"
"AA, 10 years."
死人  戒酒
Dead and sober.
愈加怪异了
Double crappy.
他有份固定的支出
There's a charge keeps coming up.
每月支付简之花五十美元
50 bucks a month at a place called Jane's.
好吧
All right.
恭喜你  你去戒酒协会
Congrats on your sobriety.
我去调查简之花是什么地方
I'll go find out what Jane's is.
因为斋期我放弃戒酒协会
I gave up AA for lent.
我们又不是天主教徒
We're not catholic.
你就一定要追根究底吗
Always with the details.
戒酒协会让我毛骨悚然
AA gives me the jeebs.
真没想到
Wow. Shocker.
好吧
Fine.
我去调查戒酒协会  你去泡简
I'll hit the meeting. You go hit on Jane.
马特是个好人  只是灵魂饱受折磨
Matt was a nice guy. Kind of a tortured soul.
加入了我们
Join the club.
但他生活中似乎有很多烦心事
But he just seemed to have a lot going on.
知道是什么事情吗
Any idea what it was?
家人还是女朋友
Family, a girl?
他一直三缄其口
He played it all pretty close to the vest.
上次见他的时候好像什么事情困扰着他
Something was eating at him, though, the last time I saw him.
-他差点前功尽弃  -什么时候
- He almost slipped. - When?
我想应该就在他死前吧
Just before he died, I guess.
他从尼尔的酒馆给我打电话
Called me from Neal's tavern.
说他差点就喝酒了
Said he was an inch away from drinking.
我跑过去  制止了他
So I ran over, talked him off the ledge.
那你知道是什么造成的吗
Well, do you know what triggered it?
我说过了  他不喜欢与人分享
Like I said, he didn't share much.
我能帮你吗
May I help you?
是的
Uh, yes.
我要问你一些关于你客户的问题
I just had a few questions about a customer of yours,
客户名字是马修·哈蒙德
name of Matthew Hammond.
好的  他没惹麻烦吧
Uh, sure. He's not in trouble, is he?
实际上  哈蒙德先生已经过世
Actually, Mr. Hammond is no longer with us.
这样就说的通了
Now it all makes sense.
什么说的通
What does?
几天前他来过
He came in, couple days ago,
给了我三年的预付款以保证每月继续送花
paid me three years in advance to keep his monthly delivery going.
花送去哪里
Where do the flowers go?
伊丽莎白·杜仑小姐
A Miss Elizabeth Duren.
你可以将伊丽莎白的地址写下来吗
You mind writing Elizabeth's address down?
我要去拜访她一下
I'd like to pay her a visit.
我们到了
Here we go.
见一下伊丽莎白·杜仑
Meet Elizabeth Duren.
享年十岁
Died at 10.
那她究竟是谁
So, who was she?
不知道
I don't know.
我们还是回旅店再研究吧
Why don't we chew on it back at the motel?
伊丽莎白·杜仑
Elizabeth Duren.
十年前被害
Killed 10 years ago
一个邻居在车道上倒车的时候
When a neighbor backed out of his driveway,
没看到她在骑车
didn't see her bike.
没人遭到起诉
No one was ever charged.
-警方认定为交通意外  -让我猜猜
- Police ruled it an accident. - Let me guess.
那个邻居就是十楼上被撞成肉饼的
The neighbor's our tenth-floor pancake.
至少我们知道他为此很难过
At least we know he felt bad.
他送的花...
I mean, the flowers...
让人不禁怀疑那家伙撞人的时候
Kind of makes you wonder if the guy wasn't drunk
有没有喝醉
when he ran her over.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧  不管怎么样
All right. Well, regardless,
鬼车事件总算有条靠谱的线索了
now that we got a decent bead on ghost rider,
走吧
let's go.
干嘛
What?
烧掉她的骨头
Burn her bones.
让死者安息
Put her to rest.
真是没完没了
The fun never stops.
别让那畜牲靠近我
Keep that thing away from me!
好了
All right.
这里是911  您有什么紧急情况
911. What is your emergency?
我需要帮助  有只狗在追我
I need help. There's a dog after me...
请问您所在的位置
What is your address?
我不知道  我...
I don't know! I'm --
不知道哪儿的一个餐馆里面
Some restaurant somewhere. I'm --
先生
Sir?
您在听吗
Hello?
先生  您能听到我说话吗
Hello, Sir? Can you hear me?
不
No.
no!
先生  请您保持镇定
Sir, you need to calm down.
医务人员很快就能到  请说出您所在的位置
We'll send the paramedics. Just tell me where you are.
先生  您在听吗
Sir? Sir?
又忙了个通宵
Ohh, another night at the office.
不如你先去洗吧
Why don't you take the first shower?
听听这个
Listen to this.
一个名叫克里斯托弗·费舍的本地居民
"A local man, Christopher Fisher,
昨晚遭到野生动物攻击  全身都被撕烂
was ripped to shreds in a wild-animal attack last night."
外面很危险
It is a dangerous world out there.
他在一家餐馆的洗手间里
He was in the restroom of a diner.
这就不太对头了
Yeah, that doesn't sound right.
里面的顾客什么都没有看见
Apparently, none of the patrons saw anything.
那人报了警  大喊什么有狗
Guy calls 911, screaming about a dog,
但是接线员什么都没有听见
but the operator didn't hear anything, either.
看来这家伙跟狗还有渊源
Looks like this guy had a history with dogs.
怎么说
Meaning?
五年前  他因为组织斗狗活动遭到逮捕
Five years ago, he was arrested for running a dog-fighting operation.
好极了
Classy.
好吧
All right.
然后呢  他罪行累累
So, what? He causes so much misery
一头罗特韦尔犬死而复生  找他报仇来了
that some rottweiler goes cujo on him from beyond the grave?
等一下  狗也变成鬼吗
Wait a second. Do... dogs even have ghosts?
头一回听说
First I've heard of it.
听起来好奇怪  鬼狗
That sounds weird. "Ghost dog"?
还是鬼车更诡异  对吧
No weirder than "ghost car," you know?
这么说就通了
You know what does make sense?
报复那个对你做迈克尔·维克(美国橄榄球球星)那一套的人
Vengeance on the guy that Michael Vick'd you.
我这人不喜欢说三道四
I mean, I'm no one to judge,
但是我觉得这是那家伙自作自受
but it sounds to me like that guy had it coming.
也许是
Maybe...
也许不是
But maybe not.
他被捕后
So, he got busted,
判了缓刑
got probation,
在一家动物收养所做志愿者
started volunteering at an animal shelter.
-是啊  他非去不可  -最开始是被迫的
-Yeah, 'cause he had to. - At first, yeah.
但他刑满之后继续做了下去
But he kept going long after he served his time.
看起来他真心喜欢上了
Looks like he got really into it.
还募集了很多捐款
Raised a lot of money for the cause.
(流浪狗收养站感谢志愿者的帮助)
人是会变的
People change.
这话跟鬼狗说去吧
Yeah, tell that to ghost dog.
好了  换衣服出发
All right. Uh, get suited up.
我们去查验尸体
Let's go check out the body.
啥
What?
-什么  -啥  啥
- What? - What? What?
没什么  我...
Nothing. I...
你没事吧
You okay?
好得很
Peachy.
行  去吧
Yeah, let's do this.
猜猜我有什么发现
So, guess what I found.
红土
Red dirt.
指甲里面  鞋子上也有
Under his nails. On his shoes, too.
-就跟车祸那儿的地板上一样  -是啊
- Just like the car-crash guy's floor? - Yeah.
所以说  他们应该都去过附近某个地方
So, gotta be someplace around here they both walked.
苹果园
An apple farm?
没错
Yeah.
红土里面有某种东西能促进苹果生长
Apparently whatever's in red dirt makes great apples.
要是我吃苹果  肯定会很感兴趣的
Wow. I'd be so interested in that if I ate apples.
我们要找的苹果园应该很老了
So this one's supposed to be pretty old,
很可能荒废了
mostly abandoned.
有几百英亩
Few hundred acres.
几百英亩
A few hundred?!
我们要找到猴年马月啊
We're gonna be searching all year.
你还好吧
Uh...You okay?
他刚刚跳到车前面  你说呢萨姆
Guy just jumped in front of a car, Sam.
先生  你需要帮助吗
Uh, you want us to help you, sir?
好吧  不如我们先带你离开这儿
Okay, well, why don't we get you out of here
免得你横死在马路上  行吗
before you get roadkilled, huh?
行
Yeah.
沃伦  你缓一缓
So, Warren. Just, uh, take a minute.
说说发生了什么事
Tell us what's going on.
听着  我看得出你们是好人
Look -- you're good people, I can see that,
但是你们帮不了我
but you can't do anything for me.
没人能帮
No one can.
为什么
Why not?
因为超出了常理
Cause it's all impossible.
你们不会相信我的话
You won't even believe me.
说来听听
Well, try us.
我刚刚受过审判  被判死刑
I was just put on trial and sentenced to death.
你干了什么
What'd you do?
打劫了一家酒水店
Held up a liquor store.
杀了老板和老板娘
I killed the owner and his wife.
我是一时冲动  那时太年轻
I wasn't thinking. I was young.
年轻  什么时候的事儿
Young? When was this?
1981年
1981.
现在才审判你
And they just put you on trial?
不不  我刚刚出狱
No, no, I just got out of prison.
够了  你越说越没谱了
Okay, you're making less sense the more you talk.
没什么  你继续说
No, it's okay. Just...Go on.
坐了三十年牢
Did 30 years.
我刚刚获得假释
I just got paroled.
但是并没有得到解脱
Not that you're ever free of that.
我每天都会想那件事
I think about it every day.
那么  你先前在逃避什么
So, then, what were you running from?
我说过了  审判啊
Well, I told you -- the trial!
我只知道  我刚刚还在酒吧
All I know is, one minute I'm at the bar,
接着就被打了
and the next, I get jumped,
醒来后就在这个该死的法庭里
wake up in a damn courtroom.
法庭  就是那种...法庭吗
Courtroom? Like a... courtroom?
不  那儿只有一个法官
Well, no. There was a judge.
一切都太疯狂了
Everything was crazy.
那是在一个谷仓里
It was in a barn.
-在那个苹果农场吗  -没错
- At the apple farm? - Yeah.
你在哪个酒吧被掳走的
And this bar where you were grabbed?
尼尔酒馆
Neal's tavern.
和马修·哈蒙德在出车祸前去的...
Same place Matthew Hammond went before his...
是同一个地方
car accident.
你觉得可能那个斗狗的人也去过那儿
Think maybe dog guy went there, too?
你还有什么能告诉我们的吗
Is there anything else you can tell us?
你相信我
You believe me?
你们到底是什么人
Who the hell are you?
我们是...专门研究疯狂的事情的
We kind of... specialize in crazy.
那...这个法官  他有名字吗
So, uh, this judge -- he got a name?
没有
No.
但是那里有些很怪异的符号
But there was these weird symbols.
符号  你记得它们的样子吗
Symbols? Do you remember any of 'em?
你能画下来吗
Can you draw them?
我们失陪一下
Excuse us a sec.
能和你谈谈吗
Can I talk to you?
谈什么
What is it?
"谈什么"
"What is it?"
萨姆
Sam.
一个是酒驾司机  一个是"迈克尔·维克"
How about a drunk driver, Michael Vick,
一个杀人犯
a murderer?
还有呢
And?
还有
And...
什么时候咱们这么是非不分了呢
when did our black-and-white case turn to mud?
我只想说  在这件事上
I'm just saying I'm having a hard time
我实在没法不顶那些鬼
not rooting for the ghosts on this one.
不  你自己说过  这由不得我们去决断
No, you said it yourself -- it's not on us to judge.
没错  只是那都是狗屁
Yeah, except that that's complete crap.
大家心里都有杆秤
Everybody judges all day long.
我就应该无视那个家伙的所作所为吗
Look, I'm just supposed to ignore what that guy did?
我们也杀过人  迪恩  不止一两个
We've shot people, Dean -- more than two.
是的  你知道吗  如果那些鬼魂来找我麻烦
Yeah, you know what? When those ghosts come to kick my ass,
我也没话说
they've got a compelling case.
那你是要说什么  什么
So, what, you're saying -- what?
你再也不想干这活了
You don't want to work the job anymore?
我是说
I'm just saying, you know,
真希望那天不这么复杂
one simple friggin' day on the job --
这要求很过分吗
is that too much to ask?
好吧
Well, look.
我要出去一趟  试着找到那个谷仓
I'm gonna go out, I'm gonna go try and find that barn.
-你一起吗  -我去酒吧看看
- You coming? - I'm gonna check the bar.
是去干活还是喝酒
To work or drink?
还没想好
I haven't decided.
怎么了  他上哪去了
What's going on? Where'd he go?
他...一切都好
He... everything's fine.
我们一起回农场去
Look, let's go back to that farm.
不  不  不要  我不回去
Oh, no, no. No, I'm not going back.
沃伦  我需要你帮我找到那间谷仓
Warren, I need your help finding that barn.
它是红色的  非常显眼
It's red -- it stands out.
我不回去  他们就在那里
I'm not going back. They're out there.
-谁  -我杀的人
- Who? - The people I killed.
我...不  不要
I just -- no. No!
你跟着我只会更安全
You're safer with me than not.
不要
No.
好吧
Okay.
没事
Fine.
我需要你在我回来之前
I need you to stay inside this circle
都待在这圈子里  好吗
until I get back, okay?
它能保护你
It'll protect you.
怎么保护
How?
相信我就好  好吗  我是在帮你
Just trust me, okay? I'm trying to help.
留在原地别动
Stay put.
鲍比  是我
Bobby? Hey. Me.
我给你发一些符号你帮我查查
Listen -- I'm sending you some symbols to look up.
对不起
Excuse me.
今晚不醉不归
Dive sweet dive.
我现在知道为什么大家都来这儿了
Well, now I know why everybody comes here.
喝点什么
What can I get ya?
威士忌加苏打
Scotch and soda.
不加苏打了  我要一杯双份浓度的
You know, hold the soda. Make it a double.
你...你都值夜班吗
So, you -- you work the night shift?
问这干嘛
Why?
打算来这儿做常客吗
You plan on making this a regular thing?
没有  我只是有几个问题
No, I just got a few questions.
随你信不信  我是个警察
Believe it or not I'm a cop.
我信
I believe it.
你看起来挺有沧桑感的
You look like you've seen some crap.
很抱歉  我有一个星期没上班了
I'm sorry, I was off all week,
不过弗兰克明天会回来
but Frank'll be back tomorrow.
是这样
Right. Eh...
再来一杯
I'll do another.
是感情上的还是工作
Love life or job?
两杯双倍浓度一口闷  肯定有什么心事
Two quick doubles, it's something.
我叫蜜娅
I'm Mia, by the way.
蜜娅  这事不好说啊
Well, Mia, that is a complex question.
我叫迪恩
I'm Dean, by the way.
迪恩  幸好我是个有着喝不完的酒的
Well, Dean, luckily I'm like a captive shrink
着了迷的心理医生
with unlimited alcohol.
说吧
So, shoot.
你喜欢倾听别人的麻烦事吗
You like to hear people's problems, do ya?
我很好奇
I get curious.
看人来的
On occasion.
是工作上的事
Work thing.
既然你问起来了
Since you asked.
你有没有...
You ever...
你有没有不得不背着某人
You ever do something behind someone's back
做些事吗
because you had to?
你觉得不好受吗
Now you feel bad?
迪恩  如果你是逼不得已  为什么觉得愧疚呢
Well, Dean, if you had to, why feel guilty?
那没道理啊
That doesn't make any sense.
这个话匣子要是打开了
Well, you know, we don't have enough room for the worms
你这屋里都装不下
if we pop that can, sister.
你慢点喝
You may want to slow your roll there.
我酒量和小费成正比
The more I drink, the better I tip.
行  我还有一个小时下班
Yeah, well, I'm off in an hour.
别在我面前醉倒了
So don't pass out on me.
那我想我该换啤酒喝了
Well, then I think I'll switch to beer.
好主意
Good choice.
鲍比你找到什么了吗
Hey, Bobby, what do ya got?
那些涂鸦的字体  是埃及文字
Those chicken scratches -- definitely egyptian.
出自《死亡之书》(古埃及随同墓葬的圣典)
"Book of the dead."
好消息
So, good news, then.
他们有个奥西里斯(地狱判官)
They identify the God Osiris.
挺独裁主义的
Real authoritarian type.
他找上你
He gets ahold of you,
他当法官又当陪审团还负责执行死刑
he's judge, jury, and executioner.
传说他能直接看清人类的内心
Lore says that he can see directly into the human heart.
他衡量愧疚感
He weighs the guilt.
一旦他发现有一丁点
If he finds more than a feather's worth --
你就完蛋了
boom, you're done.
那他来迪尔伯恩干什么
So what's he doing in Dearborn?
看起来他总是突然出现
Well, it seems like he just pops up
做他的巡回审判  然后再次消失
and does his circuit-judge act and then disappears again.
我只了解到这些
That's all I got so far.
明白这意味着什么吗
You know what this means.
明白  必须在他再次消失之前找到他
Yeah. We've got to find him before he goes underground again.
不  你个傻孩子
No, you idjit.
意味着你们两个得赶紧跑路
It means you two got to get the hell out of dodge.
这家伙专盯自责愧疚的人
This guy hones in on people who feel guilty.
联想到谁了没有
Who does that sound like to you?
都过去那么久了  别再难为自己
It's been a while. But you owe yourself.
就是一阵小忧郁
It's nothing but a ground ball...
放下包袱
You just got to put your mitt down.
你是迪恩·温彻斯特
You are Dean Winchester.
这就是你的人生
This is what you do.
老哥  第三次留言
Dude, third message.
你最好别是喝高了
You better not be loaded.
回电话  我有要事
Call me. This is important.
迪恩  磨蹭什么呢  我...
Dean. About time, man. I --
-你好  -你是谁
- Uh, hello? - Who is this?
我刚刚
Oh, well, I just...
从地上捡的手机
I picked this off the ground,
我在这儿站了十分钟
where I've been standing for 10 minutes
它响个不停
listening to it ring.
这是迪恩的手机吗
Is this Dean's phone?
没错
Yeah.
他说好在这等我的
He was supposed to meet me here.
你在哪里  我马上过去
Where are you? I can be right there.
萨姆
Sam?
不  求求你们
No. Please.
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
求你们
Please.
是你害了我们
You did it to us.
希望他没事
Well, I hope he's okay.
你在哪里发现手机的
Now, where exactly did you find this phone?
那边
Uh...There.
谢谢
Thanks.
不是吧沃伦  这么多东西你只注意到破符号
Really, Warren? All you noticed were the symbols?
别挣扎了  温彻斯特先生
Quit squirming, Mr. Winchester.
胡迪尼(逃逸术魔术师)也弄不开
They're Houdini-proof.
现在说说你的指控  还是...
Now, you want to talk charges or...
我想说说你在酒吧整的鬼把戏
I'd rather talk about your Bukowski schtick at the bar.
怎么  清醒的不敢动  只敢偷袭醉汉
What, you can't jump a guy when he's sober?!
你跟那服务生聊得火热
You and that waitress had quite a talk, huh?
喝上几杯  心里的愧疚就全倒出来了
Get a couple drinks in you, and the guilt comes pouring out.
听墙根啊  真是厉害
Oh, eavespropping -- that's cute.
说到听墙根
Speaking of...
你就在那躲一晚上吗  萨姆
You're gonna skulk all night, Sam?
萨姆
Sam?
找人很快嘛
Nice job finding us.
我猜你也清楚我是谁了
I assume you figured out who I am, too?
对
Yeah.
要不要给我讲讲
You want to fill me in?
奥西里斯
Osiris.
埃及神祗
He's an egyptian god.
答对啦
Ta-da!
忙你的去吧  小萨姆
Now, go about your business, Sammy.
如果有人应该受审  那也是我
Look, if anyone should be on trial, it's me.
这事我说了算
That's for me to decide.
马上走开
Now go away.
他有权利请律师
But h-he has the right to an attorney...
没错吧
doesn't he?
-让我为他辩护  -这可不寻常
- Let me defend him. - Well, that's unusual.
你到底尊不尊重他的权利
Are you gonna respect his rights or not?
有何不可
Why not?
萨姆  你不是律师
Uh, Sam? You're not a lawyer.
我读过法律预科
I was pre-law.
那也是预科
Yeah, pre.
好了  我们开始吧
All right, then. Let's get started.
我要传唤的证人那是多得
Now, the list of witnesses I can call --
-数都数不清  -反对
- endless. - Objection!
你还要不要我把话说完  萨姆
Are you gonna let me finish my sentence, Sam?
不  这不公平
No. This isn't fair.
"公平"
"Fair"?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
继续
Moving on.
此事可以从简
I can make it very simple.
三名证人
Three witnesses.
-反对  -为何
- Objection! - Grounds?
传唤证人未经事先告知
Witness is being called without prior notice.
-说得好  -《傲骨贤妻》里学来的
- Good one. - I saw that on "The good wife."
很好  反对合理
Yes. Very fine objection.
驳回
Denied!
什么  为什么
What? Why?!
因为我是法官呀  孩子
Because I'm the judge, son.
别再反对了
Now stop objecting,
不然我判你藐视法庭
or I'll find you in contempt --
将你杀掉
That is, kill you.
我建议你让我继续审判
So I advise you to let me move it along.
法庭传唤证人
The prosecution calls
乔安娜·贝丝·哈维尔出庭
Joanna Beth Harvelle to the stand.
乔
Jo?
迪恩  萨姆
Dean. Sam.
好久不见
Long time.
你的姓名
State your name for the court.
乔·哈维尔
Jo Harvelle.
你与迪恩·温彻斯特是什么关系
And what is your relationship to Dean Winchester?
并肩作战
We worked together.
你是不是很仰慕他
Isn't it true that you admired him?
作为猎魔人  是的
Well, as a hunter... Yeah.
单就男人来说  他有些可恨
As a guy, he was kind of a jerk.
你将他视为导师吗
So you saw him as a mentor of sorts?
我不想这样形容
I wouldn't put it like that.
你认为是怎样的
How would you put it?
我说不清
I don't know.
我信任他
I trusted him.
所以如果你是想证明
So if you're trying to say
他是个坏人...
that he was a bad guy or something...
难吗
Was it hard?
什么
What?
与他并肩作战
Working with him...
考虑到你的感情
Considering your feelings.
不难  什么感情
No. What feelings?
为了他你什么都愿意做
You would have done quite a bit for him...
什么关都敢闯
followed him into any battle.
我知道你想说什么  一派胡言
I know what you're getting at, and it's bull.
那么让你从此走向不归路的第一次猎魔
So Dean had nothing to do with your first case,
与迪恩毫无关系咯
the one that started it all.
不是那样的
It wasn't like that.
没有感情  一丁点儿也没有吗
No feelings. None at all.
你还会选择同样的道路
You would have chosen the same exact road.
死在那间五金店里
Ended up in that hardware store,
手里拿着引爆器
holding the fuse.
你还真是有才
Oh, you're a piece of work. You know that?
一句一句引着她说出来
Putting words in her mouth --
辩护律师  管好他
Keep him under control, counsel...
不然我拔了他的舌头
or I'll remove his tongue.
该你提问了
Your witness.
乔
Jo.
你父亲跟你们一起生活过吧
Your dad... was in the life?
是的
Yes, he was.
你和他关系如何
And your relationship with him?
很好
Good.
我是说...
I mean...
你崇拜他
You idolized him.
差不多
Basically.
那么你从猎的初衷
So why'd you start,
是为了让一个你刚认识的多嘴之徒刮目相看呢
to impress some loudmouth ass you just met...
还是为追随你父亲的脚步
or 'cause you wanted to be like your dad?
恋父情结
Daddy issues.
没错
Definitely.
听着  迪恩  我不...
Listen, Dean, I don't --
好了
All right.
你们俩可以先商讨下策略
You two can have a moment to strategize.
然后我再传唤下一位证人
And then I'll call my next witness.
下一个证人是谁
All right. Who's the next witness?
他看你的样子好像你会知道
He looked at you like you'd know.
我一点儿头绪都没有
I got no clue.
这整件事就像是在上演
This whole thing's like a friggin' episode
《皮·威电视剧场》(儿童娱乐片)
of "Pee-wee's Playhouse".
传下一位证人
Next witness!
原告传唤...
The prosecution calls...
萨姆·温彻斯特出庭作证
Sam Winchester to the stand.
萨姆...
Sam...
这样的生活并非你所期待的  对吗
Not exactly the life you expected, is it?
稍有不同
Details a little different.
曾几何时  你本可以成为一名真正的律师
For a while there, you were gonna be a real lawyer,
迎娶杰西
marry Jess.
没错  很久以前的事了
Yeah, that was a long time ago.
但你是否曾退出家族事业  并过得很幸福
But were you or were you not happily out of the family racket
直到迪恩开着那辆吃油车又回到你的生活里
until Dean showed back up in that gas guzzler?
现在只能说实话
Ah-ah. The truth, now.
一言难尽
It's complicated.
一个举动却引发了一场多米诺骨牌效应
That one act had quite a domino effect.
回到之前话题  你的女友命丧黄泉
Come back, your girl's dead.
又不是他造成的
Well, that wasn't his fault.
没错  接下来的一切也都不是
Sure, and neither is everything that came after --
所有的牺牲  流血
all the death and the blood
以及各种命悬一线
and hanging on by a thread.
都和迪恩没有直接的关系
None of that is on Dean, directly.
但难道你没想过
But don't you think
你哥哥将你拖入这灾难性的烂摊子中
that your brother dragged you back into that catastrophic mess
是因为他宁愿拖你下水  也不愿独自承受吗
because he'd rather damn you with him than be alone?
不是的
No.
不管怎么样  我都会牵扯进来
One way or another, I'd have gotten pulled back in.
-你确定吗  -非常确定
- You know that for certain? - Pretty sure.
-"非常确定"  -我肯定
- "Pretty sure"? - I'm positive.
我相信你
I believe you.
如果是要说服我  我会说...
Hey, if it was about convincing me I would say...
什么
What?
我什么都决定不了  萨姆
I don't decide anything, Sam.
我无权决定迪恩的罪责
I don't decide Dean's guilt.
我只是权衡已有的罪责
I just weigh the guilt that's already there.
这仅关乎迪恩的个人感受
This is solely about how Dean feels,
内心深处
way down deep.
那才是突破点
Them's the breaks.
那么如果迪恩认为自己无罪
So, if Dean believes he's innocent,
他就无罪对吗
then he is?
"如果"
"If".
很重要的前提
A big "If".
我为何要重提旧事
Why do I bring up the past?
就是要看他是否依旧执念
To see if he feels like dog food about it.
人们渴求接受批判
People want to be judged.
他们的确如此
They really do.
如果你心已满负罪责  我来告诉你
When your heart's heavy, let me tell you,
真正的惩罚是释然的良药
real punishment's a mercy.
我想传唤迪恩出庭
I want to call Dean to the stand.
你现在想了
Oh, you do, now?
但这种东西总讲究个先来后到
There is an order to this stuff, you know.
那行  我允许
Okay. I'll allow it.
迪恩...
So, Dean...
你来找我的时候
when you came and got me,
你知道杰西会死去吗
did you know Jess would die?
或者其他任何事
Or any of it?
-当然不知道  -没错
- 'course not. - Right.
怎么可能呢  难道你能通灵吗
How could you? I mean, are you psychic?
这是个需要回答的问题
That's a question.
不能
No.
-当然不能通灵  -很好
- Uh, definitely not psychic. - Great.
那么为何要因无法预测未来而  而自责呢
So why would you feel guilty about not predicting the future?
没错  这确实说不通
Yeah, I guess that doesn't make any sense.
事实上  没错  不  我没罪恶感
Actually, yeah, no, I don't.
那乔呢
What about Jo?
是你杀死了她吗
Did you actually kill her?
不是的
Uh, no.
这么说吧  你对她并无内疚
Isn't it true that you don't feel guilty about her --
而只是...对她的死感到难过  对吗
that you're just...sad she's dead?
只是感觉这...糟透了
That it just...blows?
事实上...
Actually...
也许  没错
Maybe, yeah.
挺有范的  萨姆
I like your style, Sam.
十分有魅力
Very engaging.
迪恩
Dean,
所有这些  你都真的感觉责任在你吗
does any of this feel like it's really...on you?
不尽然
Not really.
那你是内心背负了罪恶感而沉重无比
Then is your heart heavy with guilt
还是只是沉重而已  与这家伙无关
or just plain heavy and none of this guy's business?
你说的...后者
Uh, what you said -- the second thing.
我问完了
Then I rest my case.
非常棒...你们都很棒
Very good... Both of you.
好了
All right.
我确实欣赏了一出好戏
Because I really enjoyed that,
作为回报  我想征询你的意见...
I'm gonna be generous and ask --
迪恩  你希望我传唤最后一位证人吗
Dean, do you want me to call my last witness?
我知道你并不想放她走的
I know you didn't want to let her go,
但把她放走是对的
but it was the right thing to do.
不客气
No problem.
或者就到此为止
Or have we had enough?
他究竟在说些什么
What the hell's he talking about?
《甜心俏佳人》(女性为主的温馨律政剧)扮够了吧  一锤定音吧
Enough Ally McBealing. Just drop the hammer, will ya?
等等  迪恩
Wait, Dean,
他在给我们时间
he's giving us more time!
不会有什么改变的  萨姆
It's not gonna make a difference, Sam!
你们还需要讨论会吗  还是已经好了
You need another moment? You done?
法庭已达成一致裁判
The court's reached a verdict.
迪恩·温彻斯特被叛
I find you, Dean Winchester,
心负罪责...
guilty in your heart...
并处以死刑
and sentence you to die.
我建议你尽快处理后事
I'd suggest you get your affairs in order quickly.
该死  我告诉过他
Damn it, I told him.
奥西里斯怎么着都会找到他
Osiris would have got to him one way or another.
那家伙实在厉害
Guy's batting a thousand.
还有时间  我们能想出办法
There's still time. We can figure something out.
鲍比
Bobby.
你查到什么了
What do you got?
能让奥西里斯翘辫子的方法
A way to give Osiris a dirt nap.
很好  我们急需
Good. We need it.
据我所知
Now, as near as I can figure,
至少能让他沉睡两个世纪
it ought to put him down for a couple of centuries, at least.
自从法老强势后这方法还奏效过好几次
It's worked a few times since the pharaohs were big.
这么说这只是暂时的了
So it's temporary?
很长的暂时
Long temporary.
我说咱们不如先这么凑合
I say we slap that band-aid on
然后跑去向外星猎人寻求彻底解决办法
and leave finding a cure to some hunter in a space suit.
你得用公羊角捅他
Now, you're gonna need to stab him with a ram's horn.
公羊角
A ram's horn?
迪尔伯恩哪来的公羊角
Where am I gonna find a ram's horn in dearborn?
不知道
No clue.
但是那玩意一定要锋利
But make sure it's a sharp piece.
他可不会给你第二次机会
He ain't gonna let you stab him twice.
好吧  谢了
Yeah. Thanks.
公羊角
Ram's horn.
好吧
Okay.
看起来  犹太人每年都会吹响它
Apparently, jewish people blow through them once a year.
这么晚了你上哪去找
Where you gonna find one this time of night?
犹太教堂
Synagogue?
要从教堂偷一个吗
You're gonna steal from a temple?
你又打破下线了
Well, that's a new low.
你现在是死囚  迪恩
You're on death row, dean.
别嘻嘻哈哈了
Quit joking around.
钥匙拿来  我去去就回
Here. Keys. I'll be back.
那混蛋会派乔来对付我  萨姆
The dick's gonna sent jo after me, sam.
你是个猎手  迪恩
You're a hunter, dean.
你知道怎么对付鬼魂
You know how to deal with ghosts.
你是要我再杀她一次吗
So, you suggesting I kill her again?
你没杀过她  迪恩
You didn't kill her, dean.
我快去快回
I'll hurry.
你可以出来了
You can come out now.
我想你不是来接受戒礼的
I'm guessing you're not here for bar mitzvah lessons.
你知道我不会这么做的
You know I'd never do this.
我知道
I know.
我想这是他的怪癖
I guess it's his thing.
扭曲的以眼还眼什么的
Some kind of twisted eye for an eye.
没关系
It's okay.
不  不是的
No, it's not.
你命不该如此
You deserve better.
不  你才是
No, you did.
你命不该如此  乔
You deserved better, jo.
迪恩  我过得很好
Dean, my life was good.
真得
Really.
他是对的
He was right, you know --
那混蛋法官  关于我的事
That dick judge, about me.
他不对
No, he wasn't.
你只是个孩子
You were a kid.
不是的
Not true.
你和萨姆
You and sam.
我只是  你知道
I just -- you know,
猎人没有童年
hunters are never kids.
我就没有
I never was.
我甚至想都没想
I didn't even stop to think about it.
不是你的错  那不是你的责任
It's not your fault. It wasn't on you.
但我不想独自承受
No, but I didn't want to do it alone.
谁想呢
Who does?
我本该
No, the right thing
送你回你妈那里去
would have been to send your ass back home to your mom.
就好像你能做到似的
Like to have seen you try.
他倒是说对了一件事
He was right about one thing.
哪件  你爱上我了
What, your massive crush on me?
讨厌
Shut up.
你肩负了太多不必要的烂摊子  迪恩
You carry all kinds of crap you don't have to, dean.
死后我看得更明白了
It kind of gets clearer when you're dead.
这么说的话
Well, in that case,
你应该能看到我心里有九成烂事
you should be able to see that I am 90%... crap.
我摆脱掉那些又能怎样
I get rid of that, what then?
你真想不去探究一下就死吗
You really want to die not knowing?
迪恩
Dean.
怎么
Yeah.
是时候了
It's time.
别傻了  迪恩
Come on, dean.
我猎杀过鬼魂  我知道那点花招
I used to hunt ghosts. I know the tricks.
他逼我做的
He's making me do this.
没关系的
It's okay.
乔
Jo?
话说  她看起来
So, it seem like... You know, like...
她看起来痛苦吗
She was in pain?
不
No.
只是有点苍白  乔平时的样子
No, just kind of faded. Regular jo.
其实  可能更快乐了点
Actually, maybe a little happier.
我有个问题
I got a question.
你怎么想的
So where the hell did that come from,
请愿为我辩护
volunteering to defend me?
他要赶我走呢
He was gonna kick me out.
说不准  在另一种人生中
I don't know, man -- in another life,
你能当个不错的金装混蛋
You might have made a pretty decent scuzzbag.
我可是第一次  迪恩
I'm 0 for 1, dean.
那也不是你的错
Ah, it's not your fault.
你挺有说服力的
You were pretty convincing.
他说的是谁啊
So, who was he talking about?
什么
Who?
那什么最后的证人
That whole final-witness thing.
不知道
No idea.
可能是任何一个因我们而死的人
Honestly, that could be just about anybody dead we know.
还有
By the way...
我知道为什么法官大人要审判我
I mean, I get why judge judy put me on trial --
我浑身透着罪过的气息
I got guilt coming out of my pores.
但是为什么他不审你
But...Why'd he skip you?
我想  可能是我不再感到内疚了吧
I think I just don't... Feel guilty anymore.
你看  我不知道怎么和你形容  迪恩
Look, I don't know what to tell you, dean.
我很长一段时间都感觉很糟糕
I mean, I've spent a lot of time feeling pretty crappy --
貌似是一生的时间
Like, my whole life.
你私藏幸福药了吗
What, you got a secret stash of happy pills?
地狱
Hell.
可能这很荒唐
Look, I'm not saying it's logical.
只是  我觉得我做了很多
I just...You know, I feel like I did a lot of stuff
该为之愧疚的事
I should have felt bad for,
然后我又偿还了
and then I paid a lot of dues
就不再欠这个债了
and came out the other side, you know?
就这样吗
And that worked?
你感觉你是一笔勾销了吗
I mean, you really feel like your slate's wiped?
没有
No.
不可能会一笔勾销的
Nothing ever gets wiped. You know?
有时我在刷牙的时候会看到路西法
Sometimes I see lucifer when I friggin' brush my teeth,
但是  我终于觉得
but, I don't know, I guess I just finally feel like
过去的就过去了
my past is my past,
我能继续过我的生活了
and I can move on with my life.
希望如此
You know, hopefully.
说得容易做的难
Easier said than done.
确实
Not arguing that.
我不知道是要嫉妒还是觉得诡异
Well, I don't know whether to be jealous or weirded out.
你会习惯的
You'll get used to it.
我不想听起来很差劲
I mean, I don't want to sound lame,
但是我感觉很爽  迪恩
but...I kind of feel good, dean.
反正跟你一起会开心就是了
Well, you are going to be a pleasure to ride with.